<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Thoughts from Anthony Dillon</title>
  <subtitle>I love to learn and teach others, I&#39;m always looking for new ways to improve myself. I&#39;m a big fan of the leanweb community.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://anthonydillon.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://anthonydillon.com/"/>
  <updated>2022-07-13T16:55:49Z</updated>
  <id>https://anthonydillon.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Anthony Dillon</name>
    <email>me@anthonydillon.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Ant FM</title>
    <link href="https://anthonydillon.com/ant-fm/"/>
    <updated>2022-07-13T16:55:41Z</updated>
    <id>https://anthonydillon.com/ant-fm/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The idea for Ant.FM came from me switching from listening to music on the free Spotify (with ads) to listening to music on Youtube. Youtube provides most music ad free, but requires me to re-visit the web page to select the next track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to build a site that can queue up youtube video’s and play them one after another. Whether it is the full album, top tracks from an artist or a playlist the user has created.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Handling “class” attribute in Beautifulsoup</title>
    <link href="https://anthonydillon.com/handling-class-attribute-in-beautifulsoup/"/>
    <updated>2022-07-13T16:55:41Z</updated>
    <id>https://anthonydillon.com/handling-class-attribute-in-beautifulsoup/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Using the docs it can be difficult to spot the syntax to find an element with a class. Here is how you refine your search to the elements with my-image class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;img = soup.findAll(&amp;quot;img&amp;quot;, { &amp;quot;class&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;my-image&amp;quot; })
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crummy.com/software/BeautifulSoup/bs4/doc/&quot;&gt;Beautiful Soup Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Leading distributed teams</title>
    <link href="https://anthonydillon.com/leading-distributed-teams/"/>
    <updated>2022-07-13T16:55:41Z</updated>
    <id>https://anthonydillon.com/leading-distributed-teams/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi my name is &lt;strong&gt;Ant&lt;/strong&gt; and I have work at Canonical the company behind Ubuntu for over 10 years now. All of which I worked in the office. For the last 7 years I have been a manager of a mix of in office-based and remote team members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Unexpected challenge over the last 12 months&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used to hold company get together called Sprints within Canonical. In which, a large portion of the wider company would all get together for a week of meetings, planning and socialising. Over the past year and a bit we have not been able to do this and has led to a weaker cross team relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last few Sprint weeks have been held remotely which does not allow for hallway discussions and organic team building and idea sharing/forming over coffee or dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the last Sprint we were talking about a technical challenge which lead me to think of how that could positively effect another project. I would normally wait to the end of the meeting and catch the person working on the other project on the way out and explain the idea as we grabbed coffee before the next meeting. In this case, we both just closed our call and left it there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How do you keep remote and distributed teams in the loop and prevent the feeling that people are siloed and isolated?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of us will say Good morning in the team chat channel when we come on board. This gives people a feeling of light touch with others is not straight into work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hold regular cross team meetings such as guild or chapter meetings which keep teams from only talking to their immediate squad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tools we use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miro&lt;/strong&gt;: for brainstorming and sharing our ideas collaboratively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figma&lt;/strong&gt;: for creating and archiving designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zeplin&lt;/strong&gt;: for presenting finalised versions of designs for comments and feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZenHub&lt;/strong&gt;: an augmentation of GitHub which provides a view of issues and PRs as a board which auto updates based on the status on GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mattermost&lt;/strong&gt;: as our internal chat system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have an internal team optional meeting were someone can put forward a session based on a topic they would like to share with everyone. These are called &lt;strong&gt;Masterclass&lt;/strong&gt; and they allow for the entire team to get together and learn and questions each other across disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What creates a productivity and collaboration in a remote environment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canonical has always been a truly global company. The teams here have been trail blaze async working processes. We developed Launchpad which is a software collaboration platform before GitHub or GitLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All teams across Canonical and the industry are different and should adapt others processes to suit there teams. The web team at Canonical is also always evolving its process but I will detail some of the structures, processes and cultural changes we have utilised over the past 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shared meetings notes&lt;/strong&gt;: we encourage all meetings to have someone taking notes of the meeting and posting them as an issue on a private GitHub repo we have all subscribed to. That way we receive a nicely formatted email when a meeting has finished and allows for searching, tagging and continued discussion. We assign the issue to anyone that has an action from the meeting and so appears on there assigned issue list. Which is a nice way to tie meeting actions with our standard working practise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Record team meetings&lt;/strong&gt;: we perform a number of rituals as a team. Such as end of iteration demos and a fun meeting at the end of each week which a number of us present something they are interested in. These meetings are recorded and shared with the team so all team members can watch the sessions and its not just a summary of the fun the team had.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviews are async&lt;/strong&gt;: as stated above in tools we use Zeplin as our tool for performing design reviews which can happen at any time by adding comments to the design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tips and processes do not just benefit teams with people in different time zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also is a huge benefit to members of the team that are more reserved and less likely to talk up in a group meeting. I appropriate the time to think though my ideas and gather my thoughts before putting forward my opinion on something. How often has a decision been made in a meeting and only later turns out the decision would have been different with more thought or discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, everyone has holiday, can be sick or are just busy. These processes allows for these members of the team to miss meetings in the knowledge they can catch up later and add any opinions they have without missing out and being left out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What do you look for in the hiring process to determine if engineers will succeed with remote work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not on an individual to succeed or fail when working remotely. It is a team effort and if someone is having trouble then it should be noticed or they need to feel safe enough to speak up on the matter. A truly good team will react positively to any troubles a team member is having. Finding ways to remedy to issues and adapt the working processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are of course exceptions but that is where the manager need to support the team member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have developed an on boarding epic which contains a number of categorised issues with list of todos and things to read. We normally give a new member of the team two weeks to step through the items and encourage them to take there time. It’s inevitably overwhelming and the best thing we can do is remove any time pressure a person might feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How do you introduce remote teammates into the organisation so they have a strong chance of being successful?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We assign a new member of the team a mentor. A mentor is generally a person that has been in the team for a while and can act as an unblocker and someone that will explain things in familiar terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One aspect of the on boarding process is to arrange and have welcome meetings with members of the team that they should know and likely to interact with. This reduces to pressure when communicating about work later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How do effective engineering managers build trust – and support individual engineers, teams, and organisations?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to allow them autonomy on the project and work they work on. No one wants projects to all move in different directions but that needs to be controlled by a strong team culture which emanates from the engineering manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For managers, 121s with reports are the most important meeting of the week. Try as hard as you can to never cancel or reschedule them. It may feel like another of many meetings for you but for the report it is likely one of there few meetings in the week and will likely be very important for them. I generally start 121s by talking candidly about life and how things are going. It’s important to build an honest friendship and rapport with them so your team member feels comfortable coming to you with any issue they may have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let’s round up by sharing one key takeaway on leading distributed teams, What’s your one piece of advice to any engineering leader?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay close to the code. It might be difficult as you may find you are no longer the expert in the room on something but you build a lot of respect and good culture by trying anything, asking simple questions and allowing the team to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a avid football player, I treat work like a game of sport. You may be the captain but that means you work as hard, keep your humility. Provide &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Servant_leadership&quot;&gt;Servant leadership&lt;/a&gt; from the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t put yourself above others in your mind, stay connected, stay friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Robin Winslow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Refocusing on 1:1s</title>
    <link href="https://anthonydillon.com/refocusing-on-1-1/"/>
    <updated>2022-07-13T16:55:41Z</updated>
    <id>https://anthonydillon.com/refocusing-on-1-1/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been grappling with the desire to improve my 1:1 meetings recently. As a manager, I want 1:1 meetings to focus on the needs of my reports and not be a status or progress report of their current work. But I don&#39;t want to burden anyone with preparing an agenda and no-agenda meeting can cause anxiety. So here are some areas I will try and touch on each week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wellness&lt;/strong&gt;: Are you safe and well? You needn’t disclose personal information, but I’m here to listen, especially if work is impacting your well-being. Do you feel physically and psychologically safe, is your work/life balance compatible with your mental health?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Readiness&lt;/strong&gt;: Are you set up to succeed? Do you have what you need to meet your goals, starting with a clear understanding of what those are? What resources (material, support, or even just help and advice) might I provide that could help you be successful?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obstacles&lt;/strong&gt;: What is standing in your way? One of my primary roles as your manager is to help identify and clear obstacles to your progress. Let’s talk about anything that is slowing you down or anything that could speed you up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recognition&lt;/strong&gt;: Since we last met, what did you accomplish that you feel good about? No achievement is too small. It&#39;s silly to scramble for a list at the end of the year. Let’s note each achievement, while they&#39;re fresh in our minds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback&lt;/strong&gt;: How I am doing as your manager? I promise to always to open and honest with you and I hope you can do the same for me. I would like to hear what I can do better and differently to become a better manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also working out how to bridge the gap between being productive and casual within 1:1&#39;s. I don&#39;t want to lose the general chit chat aspect of this calls as a good report with your reports is very important.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Surprising CSS selectors you can use today</title>
    <link href="https://anthonydillon.com/surprising-css-selectors-you-can-use-today/"/>
    <updated>2022-07-13T16:55:41Z</updated>
    <id>https://anthonydillon.com/surprising-css-selectors-you-can-use-today/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As of date of writing which was 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working on the Juju GUI project, I was reviewing a pull request when I spotted there were no prefixes on box-sizing. I thought I should check if they needed it before asking the requester to add them. In doing so I was surprised to find that there are a lot more CSS features with global support than I originally thought. So I trawled through the chasms of Can I use and have come out with some gems to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;filter: sepia(1); – 78% browser support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSS filter effects can be used to apply effects like blur, grayscale, brightness, contrast and hue. I remember a few years ago I was asked to create a blur effect as an element that overlays the page content. CSS was no help as none of the browsers supported blur. So I went on a dirty hacking weekend where I set the text to transparent, added a text shadow and used JavaScript to replace all the images with a blurred version. This worked, but I needed a shower afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was shocked to spot that today browser support is 78%, including full support for all browsers apart from Edge, IE and Opera Mini. So I could have just used the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;img {
  transition: -webkit-filter .5s;
  -webkit-filter: blur(0);
}

.overlay-active img {
  -webkit-filter: blur(1);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while this doesn’t cover all bases; it’s enough to let us drop the dirty hacks and use progressive enhancement instead. After all, it’s not the end of the world if IE users see a simple alpha transparent overlay instead of a blurred version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/#feat=css-filters&quot;&gt;http://caniuse.com/#feat=css-filters&lt;/a&gt; (WebKit prefix)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CSS3 selectors – 97.73% browser support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSS3 selectors dawned a new era of capabilities in CSS, giving us a bunch of new methods to select with logic. The more interesting selectors are explained below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[foo^=&amp;quot;bar&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt;, the carat symbol is used as a regular expression to select attributes starting with &lt;code&gt;bar&lt;/code&gt; in this case. A simple example of this features usage is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;a[href^=&amp;quot;http&amp;quot;] {
   background: url(external-icon.svg) no-repeat;
   padding-left: 10px;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we are selecting all the links that link to an external site and adding a small external icon to it automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[foo$=&amp;quot;bar&amp;quot;]&lt;/code&gt;, similarly this regular expression symbol refers to matching end of string.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;a[href$=&amp;quot;.pdf&amp;quot;]:after {
  content: “(PDF)&amp;quot;;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example demonstrates selecting a link that is linking to a PDF file and appending a notice to give the use an understanding of the expected behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;:nth-child()
, selects elements based on the occurrence of the elements. For example:

li:nth-child(n2) {
  background-color: light-grey;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example will select the every second element and apply a light grey background to it. You can also use (odd) in this case but I wanted to show the nth usage.
&lt;code&gt;:empty&lt;/code&gt;, This selector will select any element that containing nothing including HTML comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will match:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Won’t match:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;:empty&lt;/code&gt; pseudo selector is useful for hiding empty elements that can cause spacing as they have padding. It can also hide the border of an empty list item. &lt;code&gt;:not()&lt;/code&gt;, is a negative selector. It takes an element selector as a parameter. If the match is false then styles are applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;.menu:not(.is-hidden) {
  // menu styles
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;foo ~ bar&lt;/code&gt;, is a sibling combinator. Which works similarly to &lt;code&gt;foo + bar&lt;/code&gt; but is less strict. The + method will only select the first bar inside foo. Whereas the ~ select will select all bars only if it is preceded by a foo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;h2 ~ p {
  margin-top: 1em;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have been under the impression, as I was, that these selectors were not well supported. Perhaps you thought either that you could not use them, or would require some thought into a polyfill or progressive enhancement trick to use them. However, I was surprised to discover that CSS3 selectors have 97.73% global support, including IE8 and up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/#feat=css-sel3&quot;&gt;http://caniuse.com/#feat=css-sel3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Calc() – 80.75% browser support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favourite new features to CSS. &lt;code&gt;Calc()&lt;/code&gt; gives users the ability to perform mathematical calculations using different units within CSS. For example, positioning a background icon to the right of a input field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have all been there, you add a background and position the icon to &lt;code&gt;right center&lt;/code&gt;. Dust your hands, job done. You show the design and they ask for the icon to be 10px from the right of the element. Damn, its a background and you don’t want to create a new element just for a little icon. So you set the background position to &lt;code&gt;90% center&lt;/code&gt;. This falls over at different viewport sizes. Calc to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;.search-field {
  background-position: calc(100% - 10px) center;
  …
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That will do nicely. Also if you wanted a floating sidebar to fill up the entire height of the screen, apart from the header, you could use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;.sidebar {
  height: calc(100% - 50px)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a nice healthy 80.75% global support and no browser prefixes required, it’s time to add this to your arsenal of selectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/#feat=calc&quot;&gt;http://caniuse.com/#feat=calc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CSS animation – 90.29% browser support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since the death of Flash we have been looking for a replacement to animation on the web, luckily CSS animations became available very quickly after. As with all new features I was curious, but resistant to use in production without carefully considering an appropriate fallback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, CSS animations boast a healthy 90.29% support with a &lt;code&gt;-webkit&lt;/code&gt; prefix. This means there is no reason not to add some small usability aids to your UI components, such as animating a notification into view to grab the user’s attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to bring your site or web app to life by adding some subtle animation. You could add some motion to the introduction of the notification, using the following simple example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;.notification-open {
  -webkit-animation: dropDown .6s;
  -webkit-animation-fill-mode: forwards;
  -webkit-animation-timing-function: ease-in-out;
  animation: dropDown .6s;
  animation-fill-mode: forwards;
  animation-timing-function: ease-in-out;
}

@-webkit-keyframes dropDown {
  from {-webkit-transform: translate(0,-100px);}
  to {-webkit-transform: translate(0,25px);}
}

@keyframes dropDown {
  from {-webkit-transform: translate(0,-100px);}
  to {-webkit-transform: translate(0,25px);}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro tip&lt;/strong&gt;: Do not animate a positional style such as &lt;code&gt;top&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;margin&lt;/code&gt;. This will cause a page repaint and in some cases require the browser to calculate the positions of the visible elements on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/#feat=css-animation&quot;&gt;http://caniuse.com/#feat=css-animation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;@supports rule – 67.85% browser support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;@supports&lt;/code&gt; gives us the ability to check if a feature is supported and conditionally style elements based on the browser’s functionality. For example, you can use supports to detect if flexbox is supported by that particular browser and if not swap back to floats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;@supports (display: flex) {
  div { display: flex; }
}

@supports not (display: flex) {
  div { float: left; }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pairing &lt;code&gt;@supports&lt;/code&gt; with the not keyword allows for any type of logic within your CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the gotchas with this feature is most of the time we want to test an older browser for new feature support. The older browser itself will not support this type of query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment feature queries have 67.85% support. While this is not ideal, it does cover the latest versions of the evergreen browsers, which is a good start. The only browsers lacking support are IE and Opera Mini. This has the added benefit of meaning we can begin to drop the extra dependence on Modernizr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/#feat=css-featurequeries&quot;&gt;http://caniuse.com/#feat=css-featurequeries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Flexbox – 95.4% browser support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one feature I’ve heard nothing about. Only joking! It’s talked about in hundreds of blog posts and conferences. It’s a fantastic tool to position elements either stacked horizontally or vertically, giving us the ability to easily centre elements or make elements all the same height. It also allows us to change the order in which the elements are displayed on the page. Have you ever been asked to swap the order of the image and text of a section when on small screen. I have — flexbox to the rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;@media only min-width(768px) {
  .row {
    display: flex;
    flex-direction: column-reverse;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I was a little wary of using it for anything important because, like all of these things, I didn’t believe its support was good enough. Flexbox proudly boasts a huge 95.4% browser support, spanning all the latest browsers, including Opera Mini. IE9 and below will miss out but when using it for aesthetics, that’s probably ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/#feat=flexbox&quot;&gt;http://caniuse.com/#feat=flexbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3D transforms – 89.87% browser support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature allows us to position an element in the third dimension. This feature also includes the perspective property, allowing us to set the z-index of a 3D element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve all seen awesome examples of 3D scenes using just CSS, but the level of browser support took me by surprise. With an impressive 89.87% global support with a single prefix of webkit, it is ready to be used today in production. I would suggest dropping the fallback, as in most cases the functionality of a 3D element will be aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick example of a card that would spin and flip as you hover over it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot;&gt;.card {
  -webkit-transform-style: preserve-3d;
  transform-style: preserve-3d;
  -webkit-transform: rotateX(0deg) rotateY(0deg);
  transform: rotateX(0deg) rotateY(0deg);
  transition: transform 1s;
}

.card:hover {
  -webkit-transform: rotateX(180deg) rotateY(180deg);
  transform: rotateX(180deg) rotateY(180deg);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://caniuse.com/#feat=transforms3d&quot;&gt;http://caniuse.com/#feat=transforms3d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a lot of blog posts and listen to a lot of podcasts all about frontend web development but did not realise how important it was to read through the features documented on Can I use. Truly, hats off to the people working on the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re unsure how well a feature is supported, Can I use is the holy grail. I would recommend to any frontend dev to take the time to read through all the features, their support and known feature issues. There is no better shortcut to levelling up your CSS knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you can see all the awesome stuff that can be developed using the features in this post. 2016 is the year to start using new features and create rich immersive user experiences. Whether it’s web apps or even a simple site. Never wait for “permission&amp;quot; to use new features just make sure you understand the support and consider fallbacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now go out and use them!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tips and tricks</title>
    <link href="https://anthonydillon.com/tips-and-tricks/"/>
    <updated>2022-07-13T16:55:41Z</updated>
    <id>https://anthonydillon.com/tips-and-tricks/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I think we all have handy tips and tricks we have picked up over the years so I thought I would write them down and show you. I fully expect no one to learn something but you never know. 🤷‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google Meet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ctrl + d&lt;/strong&gt; - Toggles the audio on/off&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ctrl + e&lt;/strong&gt; - Toggles the camera on/off&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you focus on the audio button, you can hit space to toggle the audio on and off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mattermost&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alt + [up|down]&lt;/strong&gt; - This moved you up and down channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shift + tab&lt;/strong&gt; will jump me to the last message in that channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ctrl + k&lt;/strong&gt; - brings up the channel switcher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;up&lt;/strong&gt; - quick edit the last message&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gmail&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turn on keyboard shortcuts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;x&lt;/strong&gt; - selects emails and can select multiple&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;y&lt;/strong&gt; - archives the selected emails&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;]&lt;/strong&gt; - when in an email will archive and move in that direction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;j&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;k&lt;/strong&gt; - when in an email will jump to the next without archiving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Oh My Zsh + Git&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gcm&lt;/strong&gt; - git commit main branch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ggl&lt;/strong&gt; - git pull origin &lt;code&gt;{branch_name}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gcam&lt;/strong&gt; - git commit -am&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ggp&lt;/strong&gt; - git push origin &lt;code&gt;{branch_name}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;grbi&lt;/strong&gt; - git rebase -i&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Byobu&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shift + f2&lt;/strong&gt; - create a horizontal split&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ctrl + f2&lt;/strong&gt; - create horizontal split&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ctrl + d&lt;/strong&gt; - close a window&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shift + [up|down|left|right]&lt;/strong&gt; - moves you around the panels&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;shift + alt + [up|down|left|right]&lt;/strong&gt; - moved the dividers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;f2&lt;/strong&gt; - creates new window/tab&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;alt + [left+right]&lt;/strong&gt; - switch tabs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;f8&lt;/strong&gt; - name tab&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>